Okay. We talked about the assumptions inherent to factor models.
Ok我们刚刚讨论了因子模型的假设条件
Now, let's derive the covariance matrix of the returns,
下面我们用
in terms of the factor returns,
因子收益 暴露度和残差项
exposures, and residual term.
推导出收益率协方差矩阵
We need this description of the return variants,
这么描述收益率方差是因为
because we want to be able to use our factor model to
我们希望使用因子模型
describe and manage the portfolio variance,
描述和管理投资组合方差
and use this information for optimization.
并利用这一信息进行优化
We'll need to use the two assumptions; one,
我们需要提出两个假设条件
that the residual of any asset is uncorrelated with the factor returns,
首先 任何资产的残差都与因子收益率无关
and two, that the residual of any asset is
其次 资产的残差
uncorrelated with the residual of any other asset.
与任何其他资产的残差无关
Before we begin, we subtract from each asset random variable its mean.
在开始之前 先用每个资产随机变量减去均值
Such that the mean of this shifted return distribution is zero.
使这个偏移收益率分布图的均值为 0
We start with this equation,
方程一开始是这样的
which is a factor model of the stock return.
它是一个股票收益因子模型
If there are many assets then r is a vector of observable random variables.
如果有很多资产 那么 r 是可观察随机变量向量
What I mean by that is,
也就是说
r1 is a random variable that represents the return of asset one.
r1 是一个随机变量 表示资产 1 的收益
It can take on any value with a probability determined by a probability distribution.
它可以是任何值 概率由概率分布确定
R, is a vector of length equal to the number of assets.
R 是一个向量 长度等于资产数量
B, is a matrix of fixed that is not random coefficients,
B 是一个固定的矩阵 不是随机系数
it has dimensions of assets by factors.
维度为资产数量 x 因子数量
F, is a vector of random variables,
f 是一个随机变量向量
each of which represents the value of a factor return.
每个变量表示一个因子收益的值
Finally, this is the vector of residuals.
最后这个是残差向量
Which as we said, are specific to the assets.
它特定于资产
So, there is a residual random variable for each asset.
所以每个资产都有一个残差随机变量
Now, we want to calculate the covariance matrix of the asset returns.
下面我们想计算资产收益率的协方差矩阵
Remember, that the covariance of
两个随机变量的协方差
two random variables can be calculated with this formula.
可以通过这个公式计算
But if the means of the two random variables are zero,
但是如果两个随机变量的均值为 0
this simplifies to the expectation value of their product.
那么可以简化为二者积的期望值
The expectation value of a matrix is just a matrix
矩阵的期望值等于
with the expectation value operator applied to each element.
将期望值运算符应用到每个元素后的矩阵
The matrix of products of asset returns,
资产收益率积的矩阵
is just rr transpose.
等于 rr^T
So, the covariance matrix can be written as the expectation value of rr transpose.
所以协方差矩阵可以写成 rr^T 的期望值
This follows by our model for r.
r 模型是这样的
First, distribute the transpose to the two terms on the right.
首先 将转置符号放到右侧的两项
Here, we just expand out the matrix product.
我们直接展开矩阵的积
Now, distribute the transposes.
然后进行转置运算
We can pull the B matrix out of the expectation function,
我们可以从期望函数里提取出矩阵 B
because it is not a random variable, it is fixed.
因为它不是随机变量 是固定的
Here, we use the fact that the residual errors
然后 我们假设
and factor returns are assumed to be uncorrelated.
残差和因子收益率不相关
The first assumption we discussed earlier.
即之前讨论的第一个假设条件
This means that the expected value of the factor returns times the errors is zero.
所以因子收益率乘以残差的期望值为 0
So, the two terms in the middle becomes zero.
中间的两项变成 0
We will now simplify our notation
接下来简化
to represent the covariance matrix of the factor returns.
因子收益率协方差矩阵方程
Finally, we write down the covariance matrix of the residuals,
最后写出残差的协方差矩阵
which we know to be a diagonal matrix.
它是一个对角矩阵
Meaning that only the variances of the residuals may be nonzero,
所以只有残差的方差可能非零
but the covariances between residuals of different assets are zero.
但是不同资产残差之间的协方差为零
The reason for this, is the second assumption from earlier;
因为第二个假设条件是
that the error random variables are assumed to be uncorrelated across assets.
各个资产的误差随机变量不相关
So, their covariances are zero.
所以它们的协方差为零